翻译：依依  Dwyer  Ellen
翻译：微云  雕刻时光  sin_city
翻译  校对：凡凡  幸福ing
翻译  校对：江米球  老马
组长：火星人善良凡凡
监制：幸福ing形式
———— 祝大家观影愉快 ————
真令人印象深刻
Impressive.
能够放倒自己两倍体格守卫的
Not many recruits could take down
新人可不多见
a guard nearly twice their size.
他接受过出众的格斗和体能训练
He had the superior training and conditioning.
你却只能靠你的直觉
All you had were your instincts.
还有你的牙齿
And your teeth.
一般来说 这种行为
Normally, such actions would be cause
我们会立马取消资格
for immediate cancellation.
但是你刚来了没几天
But you've only been here a few days,
而且组织存在的意义就是给人第二次机会
and Division is all about second chances.
- 我只想出去  - 当然 但是
- I want out. - But of course.
必须等到你准备好
When you're ready.
当你明白
When you learn that
暴力从来没有欺骗来的有效
brute force will never be as effective as deception.
你要么就变得非常强大而且美丽
You can either be powerful and beautiful,
要么变成一只野兽
or you can be a wild animal.
但是你必须做出抉择
But you have to choose.
我不能帮你决定
I can't decide for you.
那么问题就变成  你会成为哪样的人？
So the question is, who will you be?
蹲下！ 现在就蹲下！ 蹲下！
Get down! Get down now! Get down!
- 你好 Philip  - 嘿 等等 等一下！
- Hello, Philip. - Hey, wait, wait, wait!
有话好说
We can discuss this.
不能再有任何交易 任何猫腻了！
No more deals, no more illusions!
Ryan为了真相已经牺牲了自己
Ryan sacrificed himself for the truth.
现在轮到你了
Now it's your turn.
那时候还有其它人
There were others.
那时候不仅仅是我 还有其它人
It wasn't just me, there were others.
我知道
I know that.
要不我怎么会在这里？
Why do you think I'm here?
他们的名字
Their names.
这是…这是联系人文件
This is the-- this is the contact file.
这就是所有人了 全部人了
It's all of them, the entire group.
你不能让他们找到我
You can't let it get back to me.
他们会报复的  不管你把我藏在哪里
They'll retaliate, no matter where you hide me.
相信我  没有人能找到你
Trust me. No one will ever find you.
- 放倒一个了  - 还有七个
- One down. - Seven to go.
联邦政府还没有
Federal authorities have yet
对爆炸做出任何评论
to comment on what caused the explosion,
但是警官们已经确认了是在押运
but marshals have confirmed that this was the convoy
Philips Jones途中发生的
transporting Philip Jones,
他是MDK的前任首席财务官…
the former cfo of MDK...
- 她他妈在干什么？ - 你们都不敲门的吗？
- What the hell is she doing? - Don't you people knock?
都是她告诉你需要做的东西
Exactly what she told you needs to be done.
她正在引蛇出洞
She's taking out the group.
可是我告诉她的是这样一个办法…
And I told her there's a process--
调查 收集证据 然后把他们引出来
investigate, collect evidence, ferret them out.
我们不能只是跑去杀掉这些人
We can't just go around killing these people,
尽管他们都不是什么好人
even if they're dirty.
为什么不呢？ 听起来挺合理的
Why not? Sounds like a plan to me.
很难令人相信 但是还有其它办法
Hard to believe, but there are ways
可以搞定这些事情的
of getting things done
而且不会触犯法律
that don't involve illegal activities.
是  她曾经试过这个办法
Yeah, well, she tried it that way,
然后现在Ryan死了
and now Ryan's dead.
你是在说你同意这种方式吗？
You're saying you agree with this?
我的意思是… 她只是刚刚开了个头
What I'm saying is... She's just getting started.
所以我们给了她
So we've given her
总统自由奖
the Presidential Medal of Freedom,
而且她现在已经是国民英雄了
and she's a national hero.
现在她正在外面暗杀
Now she's out there assassinating
世界前500强的特授成员
charter members of the Fortune 500.
请你一定帮我按摩下脖子  好吗？
Be sure you get my neck, would you?
一定的
Of course.
我们的政府禁止暗杀…
Our government forbids the assassination--
不要搞笑了
Don't make me laugh.
是我们的政府训练她成为一名刺客的
Our government trained her to be an assassin.
而且她从不会失手
And she never misses her target.
那又怎样？
So what?
Nikki正在扫清那些企图杀掉Ryan
Nikki's wiping out the elites
然后想引起第三次世界大战的精英？
that killed Ryan and tried to start World War III?
不 我们可不想这样
Oh, no. We don't want that.
就算Ryan Fletcher的推断是对的
Let's say Ryan Fletcher's intel is correct,
这个组织已经在世界各地
and this group has planted 54 doubles
安插了54个担任要职的复制品
in key positions of power around the world.
当Nikita杀了那些傀儡后
What happens after,
又会发生什么？
when Nikita kills the puppet masters?
由其他被操纵者代为掌权
There would be sleeper agents operating off book.
军事人员  管理家  政治家
Military officers, executives, politicians--
所以你得让我们离开基地
this is why you need to get us off the base.
我们是唯一能把控她的
We're the only ones who can reign her in.
- 我不这样认为  - 你找不到她的
- I don't think that's-- - You are not gonna find her.
Sonya正在用“影网”找她
Sonya's already looking for her through Shadownet,
但我们现在做的太有限了
but there's only so much we can do from a desk.
我们需要脚踏实地  才能找到她
We need to be on the ground. That's how we'll find her.
但我们何必呢？
Yeah, but why should we?
听着 Nikita想把一切
Look, Nikita wants to reduce
归结为零
the 1% of the 1% to 0...
我们就悠闲旁观  嚼着小吃
I say pull up a chair and pass the popcorn.
你真想无辜的人死吗？
You really want innocent people to die?
因为那就是即将会发生的
Because that is what is going to happen.
拜托  Mikey  她不会任其发生的
Come on, Mikey, she wouldn't let that happen.
你真以为你了解她吗？
You really think you know her now, huh?
但当时  你并不在那里
But you weren't there in the very beginning.
你并未亲眼见证她的到来
You didn't see her when she first came in.
这是她这一周第四次闹事儿
This is her fourth incident in her first week,
Damon也失去了半拉耳朵
and now Damon's missing half his ear.
谁都知道Damon喜欢到处招惹姑娘
Everyone knows Damon likes to knock the girls around.
是时候有人教训下他了
It was inevitable one of them decided to knock back.
那继门卫事件后
Well, it's one thing to go after a guard.
她又袭击了一个想向她伸以援手的人
It's another to attack someone who's trying to help her.
她需要培训  和其他新人一样
She needs training, like any recruit.
不 这个不同
No, this is different.
她不为目的而斗争
She doesn't fight for a purpose.
她就像是为摆脱体内的另一个自己
She fights as if something's trying to get out of her.
她就是…
She's...
独特的
Special.
是危险的
Dangerous.
我会给Percy说
I'm going to recommend to Percy
我们的损失  并除去她
that we cut our losses and cancel her.
在我们整个对话过程中
You know, the entire time we were talking,
她都在试图想办法宰了我
she was trying to figure out a way to kill me.
她的战术直截了当
Her tactical sense is intuitive.
如果我们能利用这个天赋
If we could just harness that talent,
她将是组织最优秀的特工
she could be the greatest agent Division's ever known.
但如果我们不能控制好
But if we can't control it,
她就是毁灭我们的武器
she could be the weapon that destroys us all.
这能证明什么？
What does that prove?
她确实摧毁了组织  不对吗？
She did destroy Division. What's wrong with that?
这不关乎组织啊  训练或者Amanda什么的
It's not about Division or training or even Amanda.
是Nikita  是内心深处的她
It's about Nikita and what is deep inside of her.
那是…她的黑暗面
It's...A darkness.
Amanda给她展现了美好
Look, Amanda showed her happiness,
但最终  她又偷走了所有
the finish line-- and she stole it all away.
这足以让任何人变得疯狂
I mean, it's enough to turn anybody upside down.
十年前  我说她可以
Ten years ago, when I said she could end up
摧毁所有  我是说组织
destroying us all, I was talking about Division.
但现在  我说的是世界
But now, I'm talking about the world.
我那么深爱她  我不会让这发生
As much as I love her, I-I can't let that happen.
阻止她
Stop her.
用尽全力
Do whatever you have to do.
尼基塔  大结局
——— 真爱字幕组 ———
你说她不会来找我们的
Yeah, well, you said she wouldn't come after us.
我低估了
I underestimated
- 她的绝望  - 太好了
her desperation. Great.
那你能确定下
Can you just make sure to let
Howorth  Wells和Kwon知道这事儿吗？
Howorth, Wells, and Kwon know that?
哦  等等  你不能
Oh, wait, you can't.
他们都死了
They're dead.
目前的首要任务就是确保
The priority at the moment is to make sure
你和其他组织成员安然无恙
you and the rest of the group remain safe.
Nikita的强项就是各个击破
Look, Nikita works best when she can divide and conquer.
我建议你别小瞧她的做法
I suggest you deny her that approach
小心为上
and fortify to a single location.
这里绝对安全
Well, this place is totally off the grid.
是通过一些控股公司挂名
I ran it through a dozen shell companies,
登记处不会有我的名字
so it wouldn't show up under my name.
很好
Perfect.
我着手准备一些方案
I'll come prepared with some recommendations
- 看看如何对付Nikita - 别
on how to deal with Nikita. No.
我会联系其他人
I'll call the others,
我们会想出办法
and we'll figure out Nikita.
然后再和你讨论
And then we'll discuss you.
我
Me?
这个团队从未失手
This group has enjoyed success
绝对保密
from a position of absolute secrecy
世世代代如此
for generations.
而这一情况开始改变
All that started to change
是因为你加入了
once we brought you on board.
这可不是我的缘故
I hardly think I can be blamed.
听着 我会为你收拾烂摊子
Look, I'll bottom-line it for you--
但这次会议只许决策者参与  明白吗
this meeting is for decision makers only, all right?
事实证明你不适合做决策
Your history shows you're not someone who can be in charge.
这不在你能力范围之内
It's just something you're not capable of.
但我会为你美言几句
Hey, but I'll put in a good word for you.
我的能力可不是你能估量的
You have no idea what I'm capable of.
这是上一个受害者那里发现的
From our last victim.
同Sam跟我在苏黎世
Same as the one that Sam and I found
商店人员身上发现的一致
from a shoperative in Zurich.
很好
Great.
希望他们
Let's hope they're on the same
计划没变
friends and family plan.
有发现
I got something.
一条信息
A message.
Trevor Adrian似乎召开了会议
Looks like Trevor Adrian called a meeting.
这是GPS定位
These are GPS coordinates.
在宾厄姆顿附近
Somewhere near Binghamton.
几小时的路程  很快可以到达
It's a few hours away. We can be there soon.
Nikita 你确定这么做？
Nikita, you sure about this?
这是个绝佳机会
It's perfect.
他们全聚集在同一个地方
They'll all be in the same place.
那前排突击是什么意思
Right, which means a frontal assault.
不再暗地里
Not picking them off one by one
各个击破了？
from the shadows anymore.
现在你好不容易摆脱关注的焦点
So far we've managed to keep your name out of the news.
但这样做  又会引人注意了
But this? This will get loud.
那就这样吧
Let it get loud.
你知道无论发生什么  我都与你同在
You know that I'm with you, no matter what.
如果你想侵略月球
You want to invade the moon,
我会准备火箭飞船
and I will find the next rocket ship.
但请你
But please,
认真考虑你将要做的选择
think about the line that you're about to cross.
你好不容易洗清罪名
You fought so hard to clear your name,
成为了真正的自己
and you're finally being recognized
一名英雄
for who you really are-- a hero.
Alex
Alex,
你总说你从这里学到很多
you've always said that you've learned so much from me.
你知道吗 我也一样
And you know what, I've learned a lot from you too.
我学会了
I've learned to...
停止逃避真实的自己
Stop running from who I am,
像你一样完全接受自己
embrace my identity the way you have.
也是这样  我知道我并非英雄
That is how I know I'm not a hero.
Birkhoff  打开影网
Birkhoff, get Shadownet up and running.
好的  可能需要几分钟
All right, might take a minute.
Sonya给了我们NSA服务器地址
Sonya's getting us an uplink to the NSA's sat servers,
可以让我们卫星追踪
give us an eye in the sky.
- NSA? - 对
- NSA? - Yeah.
我爸给了我帐号
Dad gave me access.
我们现在是官员了  记得吗
We're official now, remember?
- 给我枪  - 什么？
- Give me a gun. - What?
给我枪 有人
Give me a gun. We got company.
给我枪
Give me a gun.
喔
Whoa.
放松
Easy.
退下
Stand down.
Colonel Slocum？
Colonel Slocum?
- 谁？  - 来自悍将办公室的
- Who? - From the JAG office.
在基地时曾审问过我们
He interrogated us back at the base.
那是执行任务
That was a debrief.
和审问感觉稍有不同
An interrogation would feel a bit different.
- 你是来这审问的吗？  -监管吧
- You here to interrogate? - Supervise.
依照Chappell议员的指示
Per Senator Chappell's request.
我们自己就可以了
We're fine on our own.
你们别无选择
It's not an option.
这不是寻找郊游时走失的队员
This isn't a field trip to find a lost camper.
这是国家安全的问题
It's a matter of national security.
知道吗  悍将长官
You know what, JAG officer,
我们受够了你的士兵风格了
we've had enough of you soldier types.
为什么你不带着你的两个军队
Why don't you take your army of two
到某个地方互相缴了枪支
and go clean each other's gun somewhere?
你不明白  你们还没被释放呢
You don't get it. You haven't been released.
你们现在只是在一个临时通道上
You're out on a temporary pass,
意味着你们还在我们的负责范围之内
which means you are still our responsibility.
你们过去可能在全球范围内
You may be used to breaking laws
干着违法勾当  从现在起不再是了
all over the planet, but not anymore.
这现在属于一个军事行动
This is a military operation now.
这是最后一个
That's the last of them.
人全齐了
They're all here.
那是什么玩意
What the hell's that?
过来
Come on.
你们两个待在那儿
You two stay here.
远离窗户！
Away from the windows now!
嗨  我们还没有正式会面呢
Hi. We haven't officially met.
我需要进入Adrian先生房子里的
I need access to the security cameras
保安监视录像
at Mr. Adrian's house.
对  就是住在州际的那个
Yes, the one upstate.
他当然知道我这样做
Of course he knows I'm doing this.
喂？
Hello?
Lionel
Lionel.
Amanda  你为什么不死下去呢？
Amanda. Why can't you stay dead?
死不适合我
It wasn't a good color on me.
- 你想要什么？  - 传递一个建议
- What do you want? - To pass along a tip.
Nikita和Alex已经进入本部了
Nikita and Alex have just infiltrated
Trevor Adrian在纽约边际的府邸
Trevor Adrian's compound in upstate New York.
在那儿的还有
Gathered there with him are
组织里剩下的三名成员
the three remaining members of their group.
你告诉我们是
And you're telling us this because...
我们有一个共同的目标
Well, we both have a common goal.
我们都想让他们离开委员会
We both want them out of commission.
- 你是说你的老大们吗  - 已经不是了
- You mean your bosses? - Not anymore.
曾一度  我以为他们会是我的好搭档
For a while, I thought they could be useful partners.
但事实证明他们只是另一伙
But it turns out they're just another group
以自我为中心且充满优越感的家伙们
of self-involved, overprivileged men
自认为他们知道如何
who think they know how best
将别人的命运玩弄于股掌之上
to control other people's destinies.
如果你这么认为的话
Well, if that's the way you feel,
那你为什么不成全Nikita呢
why don't you let Nikita finish the job?
因为她不会就此罢手的
Because she won't stop with them.
一旦她成功了  我将会是她的下个目标
Once she's through, I will be her next target.
显然  我不想见到那样的局面
Obviously, I don't want that.
我想你也不想让她那么做
I don't think you want her going down that path either.
她毫无人性地杀掉了三个人
She's murdered three people in cold blood.
如果她将Adrian的住宅
What happens if she turns
变成了屠宰场会怎么样呢
Adrian's place into a slaughterhouse?
你真的以为她的灵魂里还会
Do you really think there'll be anything left
有东西存在吗
of her soul then?
找到他了
Got him.
Trevor Adrian  Adrian工业的继承人
Trevor Adrian, heir to the Adrian industrial fortune.
列出了六处住所
Six residences listed,
都不在纽约边际
none of them in upstate New York.
等等  也许有什么东西是帐外的
Hang on, maybe there's something off the books.
没错  有一部分财产和
All right, there's a few properties
账单吻合
that fit the bill.
我想我找到了
Yeah, I think I got it.
- 你找到热流了么  - 没错  多亏了Songya
- You got thermal? - Thanks to Sonya, I do.
里面有六个高热标志物
Six heat signatures inside.
聚合模式表明四个是人质
Cluster pattern suggests four are hostages.
我们去那  马上
Get us there, now.
你得搞清楚  好不？我们
You have to understand, all right? We--
我们不知道在我们日常级别的操作中出了
we don't know what goes on in our operations
什么状况
at a day-to-day level.
对不？你真正该去找的是Amanda
Right? It's really Amanda that you're after.
我马上会去找她的
I'll get to her soon enough.
不过她可不容易找到
Yeah, but she won't be easy to find.
我们把她交给你如何？
What if we give her to you?
也许我们可以做笔交易
You know, maybe we could work out a deal.
你要给我提供什么？
Yeah? You want to make me an offer?
把Ryan Fletcher还给我
Give me Ryan Fletcher back.
你能吗?
Can you do that?
喂？
Hello?
Nikita  你不用这么做
Nikita, you don't have to do this.
还有其他办法
There is another way.
我们试过其他办法  可现在Ryan死了
We tried the other way, and now Ryan's dead.
- Ryan不会打算…  - Ryan就是打算把他们抓住的
- Ryan wouldn't have wanted-- - Ryan wanted to get the group.
我这么做就是因为他的
He's why I'm doing this.
Amanda也想让你这么做
Amanda wants you to do it too.
你觉得我们是怎么找到你的？
How do you think we found you?
她想让你替她去干这些坏事
She wants you to do her dirty work for her.
你真做了这些  那她就真赢了
You do this, and she wins.
Nikita 有人过来了
Nikita, we've got company.
你带军队来了？
You sent troops?
什么?
What?
不  我们没派任何人过来  是我派的
No, we didn't send anyone. I did.
我很清楚这事
I made it very clear.
这是军方行动
This is a military operation.
继续前进！前进！
Keep going! Move!
狙击手就位
Snipers in position.
你得在有人受伤前出来
You need to come out before anyone gets hurt.
还有谁还在外面？
Who else is still out there?
侦察兵  他们正随时待命
Force Recon. And they're on a hair trigger.
你在替我拖住他们一会儿吧
Just hold them off for me for a little bit longer.
Nikita  我可不是来这妨碍你的
Nikita, I am not here to run interference for you.
我懂的
I know.
我也知道这是他们命令你这么做的
And I know that they asked you to this.
他们派你来专门联系我的
They put you up to being my personal connection.
没人命令我  我是自愿来的
No one asked me anything. I'm here on my own.
我跟你讲  快在事情没法收拾前收手吧
And I'm telling you, stop this before it goes too far.
Michael  你不会明白的
Michael, you don't understand.
我要搞到间谍的名单
I'm about to get the list of doubles.
那之后呢？你又要拿它做什么呢?
And then what? What are you gonna do with it?
我真没别的选择了
I don't really have many options,
但我今天要把这事公之于众
but I'm gonna get this out to the world today.
然后他们怎么对我也都不重要了
Then it won't matter what they do to me,
因为全世界都会知道真相
because the whole world will know the truth.
Nikita  比起其他人来说
Nikita, more than anyone,
你更清楚事情真相有多危险…
you know how dangerous the truth can be--
因此我们才要搞垮他们
This is how we destroy them.
那随之而来的危害呢？
But what about the collateral damage?
- 我不在乎！- 不 你在乎的
- I don't care! - Yes, you do.
记住你要做的是…
Remember that you do--
我需要你做点事
I need you to do something.
这是一种实验性的神经毒素
This is an experimental neurotoxin.
无嗅  无味
Odorless, tasteless.
用于人体系统
It's designed to be in a person's system
无法察觉
and be undetectable,
直到让器官变成血块
until it turns their organs into blood pudding.
你们也许认识它
Probably recognize it,
因为它就是MDK研制的
since MDK designed it.
给我间谍的名单
Give me the list of doubles,
否则你们就会看到你们的科学家们有多厉害
or you'll get to see how good your scientists really are.
谁想来一杯？
Who wants a shot?
如果你要杀我们  那就快动手吧
If you're gonna kill us, get on with it.
- 看在上帝的份上 Carl - 难道你没看到么?
- For God's sake, Carl. - Don't you see?
她在玩什么把戏吗
She's playing with us.
这不过是不值钱的小把戏
This is just cheap theatrics.
在吧台上  顶层抽屉里
Bar, top drawer.
有个夹层
There's a false bottom.
打开它
Call it up.
就是这个了…所有政客官员  外交官
That's it--every political official, diplomat,
还有军方官员  都是我们已经在这个世界上取代了的
and military officer in the world we've replaced.
绝对不能让她
Under no circumstances can she be allowed
带走名单
to get that list out of the house.
我不在乎你用什么手段
I don't care what you have to do.
必要时就鱼死网破  明白吗
Break cover if you must. Are we clear?
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
将名单发送给新闻报社
Sending it to the news outlets.
- 哪些  - 所有的
- Which ones? - All of them.
这样就可以让消息传的更远
It's gonna go so far and wide,
没人能把这个掩盖住
no one's gonna be able to cover it up.
她在寻找一个无线电信号
She's searching for a wireless signal.
她准备好传输了
She's getting ready to transmit.
少校  你们的狙击手就位没有？
Major, do your snipers have a shot?
不  不  不  先不要
No, no, no. Not yet.
Birkhoff  你准备好了没？
Birkhoff, are you ready?
马上就好
Almost there.
电磁干扰开启
Jamming field active.
Birkhoff
Birkhoff.
跟她保持通话
Keep her on that line.
为啥  你准备干嘛
Why, what are you gonna do?
计划B
Plan B.
Michael…
Michael...
停掉这个电磁干扰场   我不是Michael
stop the jamming shield. This isn't Michael.
- Sam  - 听着  我知道了  好吗
- Sam. - Look, I get it, okay?
我知道这些混蛋活该遭报应
I know these bastards deserve to pay.
但是我不得不承认  Michael是对的
But as much as I hate to admit it, Michael's right.
这不是解决问题的方法
This ain't the way.
你到底关心在乎什么
What do you care?
这对你一点儿好处也没有
There's no profit in it for you.
好吧  好吧  我活该
Okay. All right. I deserve that.
但是现在你得听我的
But now you gotta listen to me.
记得伦敦那次吗
You remember London?
我拿着黑匣子
I had a Black Box in my hand,
然后准备将里面的秘密公之于众
and I was gonna release the secrets to the world.
你阻止了我
You stopped me before I made
你现在犯得错误跟我当时一样
the same mistake you're about to make right now.
你当时精神混乱
You were suffering from regimen psychosis.
我没有  我的头脑空前的清醒
I'm not. My head is clearer than it's ever been.
这跟你的脑袋清醒是否无关
It's not about matter where your head's at.
如果Owen在这的话  他会说你受伤了
If Owen was here, he'd say you're hurting
而且  现在是时候
and that now's the time
信任那些关心你的人了
to trust the people that care about you.
他会告诉你这不是关乎你的头脑
He'd tell you it's not about your head.
是关于你的心和你的灵魂
It's about your heart and your soul.
那是Owen要说的话
That's what Owen would say.
让我接Alex的线  只接她的
Patch me in to Alex's comm and only Alex's comm.
Alex  我是Michael
Alex, it's Michael.
别让Nikita知道你能听见我
Don't let Nikita know you can hear me.
你在干嘛呢？
What are you doing?
你需要赶紧阻止她犯错误
You need to stop her from making this mistake.
这些人杀了Ryan
These are the people that killed Ryan.
你为什么保护他们  我要说的跟他们没关系
Why are you protecting them? It's not about them.
是她要公之于众的
It's about that list she's trying
那个名单
to send out to the world.
你知道她如果成功了后果是什么吗
Do you know what'll happen if she succeeds?
不  Sam  我知道自己在干嘛
No, Sam. I know what I'm doing.
告诉Michael将电磁干扰关掉
Tell Michael to stop the jamming field,
要不我就杀了他们…
or I kill them...
所有人！
All!
她说她要把他们都崩了
Hey, she says she's gonna shoot 'em.
Nikita  如果你开枪了
Nikita, if you start shooting,
海军陆战队就攻进去了
the Marines will attack.
然后你的任务就是保证
Then it's your job to make sure
我能死得其所  对不对
I don't die in vain, isn't it?
狙击手就位
Snipers have a shot.
现在进攻吗
Do we have a green light?
Nikita  求你了
Nikita, please.
我什么都没了
I have nothing left.
你要是死了  我跟你一起
If you die, I die.
好吧
All right.
好吧  我们按你的方法做
All right, we'll do it your way.
谢谢
Thank you.
让狙击手撤吧  重复一遍  解除戒备
Stand the snipers down. Repeat, stand down.
需要进入安全服务器
Need to access a secure server.
好的  Birkhoff将会打开一个数据通道
Ok. Birkhoff will open a data channel.
通过它把数据传过去
Transfer the file through it.
一旦我们接到文件
Once we receive the file,
军队就会撤退
the Marines will back off,
然后你可以安全的出来
and then you can come out peacefully.
Birkhoff  你收到了吗
Birkhoff, did you get it?
你收到文件了吗
Did you get the file?
收到了 我发到安全的地方去了
I did, and I sent it someplace safe.
你在说什么  安全的地方
What are you talking about, someplace safe?
Nikki  记得运行Red Harvest
Nikki, remember operation Red Harvest?
这样你就会知道我把文件发到哪儿了
If you do, then you'll know where I sent the file.
一样的服务器  一样的密码
Same server, same pass code.
- 你在做什么  - Nikki是对的
- What the hell are you doing? - Nikki's right.
太多的秘密和谎言
Too many secrets, too many lies.
- 把文件弄回来  - 哇哦
- Turn that file over now! - Whoa.
放松 放下枪
Relax. Put it down!
除非他把文件弄回来
Not until he turns over that file.
否则我会把你们都放倒
I will put all of you down!
冷静一下
Easy.
Nikita  你在做什么
Nikita, what are you doing?
Birkhoff给了我第二次机会
Birkhoff's given me a second chance.
我不想浪费它
I'm not gonna waste it.
不要这么做
Don't do this.
Alex
Alex!
别拦我
Get out of my way.
训练我的人想让我阻止你
The person who trained me would want me to stop you.
你曾救过我  现在我试着救你
You saved me once. Now I'm trying to save you.
我们不能发布这个文件
We can't release that file.
我是Slocum  攻击  攻击  攻击
This is Slocum. Raid! Raid! Raid!
趴下 立刻趴下
Get down, get down, right now!
她被解决了
She's down!
我投降  趴在地上
I surrender! Down on the floor!
正在押她过来
She's being processed right now.
我们把那个Udinov女人也带来了
And we brought in the Udinov woman as well.
她在D区
She's in D-block.
我也逮捕了那个黑客  已进行登记
I also arrested and booked that hacker.
名单还在这儿
That list is still out there.
如果我们有希望恢复它
If we're to have any hope of recovering it--
- Amanda怎么样了  - 这个房间没有她的踪迹
- What about Amanda? - No sign of her at the house.
议员  我请求你批准隔离F区
Senator, I requested your approval to isolate F-block.
放轻松  已经解决了
Relax. It's done.
不意味着我喜欢这么做
Doesn't mean I like it.
长官  我需要隔离整个区域
Sir, I need the entire wing to be isolated.
我们都知道她有多危险
We all know how dangerous she is.
废话少说  我知道你为什么想这么做
Oh, cut the crap. I know why you want it,
这在美国是不可能发生的
and it's not supposed to happen on American soil.
剩下的队伍呢
Now what about the rest of the team?
我并不觉得需要监管他们
I didn't see the need to bring them into custody.
放心  他们将不再是这个项目的一部分
Rest assured, they're no longer part of the process.
我想这里的防守会更加严密
Think there's gonna be a lot of security?
尽情猜吧
Take a wild guess.
有足够的火力吗  我希望这么做是值得的
Got enough firepower? I just hope it's all worth it.
Nikita现在的情况很糟
Nikita's in a real bad spot right now,
而我们不能让她呆在那里
and we kinda put her there.
她知道她处于什么状况
She knew what she was getting into.
我不会给你那个名单
I'm not giving you that list.
这里是最安全的地方
This is the most secure wing
地球上最安全的监狱之一
in one of the most secure prisons on the planet.
有钢铁加固的门的单独的监狱
Solitary cells with steel-reinforced doors,
还有不间断的巡视
and of course, constant surveillance.
尽管已经被关掉了
Although that's been shut off.
整个区域已经清空
And the entire wing's been emptied.
你在做什么  拷问我  祝你好运
For what? Torture? Good luck.
不  不是拷问
No, not torture.
我只想确认一下
I just needed to make sure
没有人看到或听到
no one would ever hear or see
这里所发生的事
what's gonna happen here.
清空人员
All clear!
你来这一定是要将刀锋对准我  是吧
You just had to twist the knife, didn't you?
不  Nikita  我是来感谢你的
No, Nikita. I'm here to thank you.
我控制了片区域的监狱
I control this wing of the prison,
多亏有你 我也在全世界
and thanks to you, I also control 54 agents
控制了54个特工
all over the world.
身居要职  手握重权  且高度忠诚于我
Highly placed, powerful, and completely loyal to me.
如果我用沙林毒气  伤亡会更大
If I use the Sarin gas, the casualties will be greater.
令人印象深刻
Impressive work.
而且他们似乎都反应良好
And they all seem to respond well.
他们都受过相同的调整
Well, they all went through the same adjustment
和你一样
you went through.
现在他们知道谁在控制大局
And now they all know who's in charge.
我仍然有那份名单
I still have that master list
在加密的云端服务器上
on an encrypted cloud server.
你没有
No, you don't.
Birkhoff不是唯一一个
Birkhoff isn't the only one
还记得怎么操作Red Harvest的人
who remembers operation Red Harvest.
名单也并不难找到
The list wasn't that hard to find.
你删除了它
You erased it?
我买了一个拥有服务器的公司
I bought the company who owns the server,
然后我关掉了整个服务器
and then I shut down the entire server farm.
就这样了  Nikita
This is it, Nikita.
就这样结束了
This is the end.
因为你  我现在是一个崭新的人
I'm a new woman because of you.
我转变了
I'm transformed.
你的脸确实变了
Your face is transformed.
那是Ryan送你的礼物么
Is that a gift from Ryan?
哦 不 这和你所受的
Oh, no, this is nothing
相比的话什么也不是
compared to what you've endured.
那些杀戮
All that killing.
我知道那会让你多痛苦
I know how it must have torn you apart,
内心的猛兽复活了
resurrecting the monster inside.
我知道因为我很理解
I know because I understand
那些黑暗是在哪里形成的
where that darkness was formed.
忍受成长对你的虐待
The abuse you endured growing up.
我懂  因为我也经历过
I know because I was formed in the same place.
但是今天  我已经超脱了这一切
But today, I rose above it all.
这并不容易
It wasn't easy.
你天生是一个领导人
You were always a natural leader.
当然  我不鼓励
I didn't encourage it, of course.
你在组织里这样做
Not inside Division.
但在你离开我以后
But after you left me,
你带走的团队
this team you put together--
他们跟随你  指望着你
they followed you, they looked to you.
Ryan把命都给了你
Ryan gave his life for you.
我必须爬到最上面
I had to claw my way to the top,
越过Percy  越过  越过暗夜
past Percy, past Oversight,
还有组织
the Group.
很久以前 我给过你一次机会
A long time ago, I gave you a choice--
暴力还是欺骗
brutality or deception.
你应该听我的  听Michael和Alex的
You should have listened to me and to Michael, to Alex.
我现在要离开你了
I'm going to leave you here...
再也不会有人看见你或听见你的声音了
Where no one will ever see or hear from you again.
但是你永远会被人们所记住
But you can take comfort in knowing
至少这点能让你得到些许安慰
that you will never be forgotten.
我拥有可以修复我这道疤的医生
I have doctors who can take this scar away.
但是我打算就这样留个纪念
But I'm going to leave it as a reminder.
不仅仅是为了你今天所作所为
Not only for what you did today,
而是为了你曾经对我造成的的每一次伤害
but for every wound you ever inflicted on me.
但是  Amanda
But, Amanda...
我没完呢
I'm not done.
Slocum
Slocum!
我不是个魔鬼
I am not a monster.
我只是想让你那么认为
I just wanted you to think I was.
给他看看  Nerd
Show her, Nerd.
我没杀任何人
I didn't kill anyone.
而且我确实听了Michael和Alex 的话
And I did listen to Michael and Alex
当然  还有你的
and, yes, even you.
对吧  Alex
Didn't I, Alex?
蛮力永远不如欺骗那么强大
"Brute force will never be as powerful as deception."
我们就是吓吓这些顶级的恶棍们
We got to scare the crap out of some top-shelf dirtbags.
他们真的以为他们就要死了
They actually thought they were going to die.
最后一个受害者
That was our last victim.
这就是我们行动的计划
The plan was to work our way
通过集团 让你知道
through the group, all the way to you.
你以为只是与我们简单交手
But you called a meeting,
把事情想得太简单
which made it that much easier.
在Adrian的房子里我们策划了一幕好戏
Adrian's house was the big show,
Adrian因此成为公众人物
and we made him the star.
所有一切都是为了得到那份名单
It was all about getting that list.
神经毒素是由河豚毒素
That neurotoxin was a modified form
改造而成的
of tetrodotoxin.
让你有濒死的症状  却不会造成持久的副作用
Death-like symptoms, but without the lasting side effects.
至于那把枪
But that gun?
哦 那是nikita的主意
Well, that was Nikita's idea.
不会致命的镇定剂
Nonlethal tranq rounds.
来见识一下真相到底如何吧
Look and sound like the real thing,
他们所做的一切都是为了将你撂倒
but all they do is put you to bed.
我们得到名单后 呆子返回工作
After we got the list, Nerd went to work.
Nikki让我连上了Adrian的笔记本电脑
Nikki gave me full access to Adrian's laptop.
我追踪到了他一直在联系的
I tracked down all the Shop facilities
“商店”使用的所有设备
he'd been talking to.
结果  发现不过是同一个而已
Turns out, it was just one.
在宾夕法尼亚西部  对不  经过改装的煤矿
Western Pennsylvania, right? Converted coal mine?
你的名册上将这些记为“复制中心”
Your roster listed it as "Replication Center."
有趣的名字
Fancy name for toy factory,
你在那儿制作你的发条玩具
where you make your little wind-up dolls.
但你喜欢保留原件 不是么
But you like to keep the originals, don't you?
没有人比我更了解她这点
Nobody knows that better than me.
但没有Slocum这些都不会发生
But none of this could have happened without Slocum.
他是我们这边的  通过他  我们找到了你
He was our audience, and through him, you.
你怎么得知他是个复制品的
How did you know he was a double?
莱恩临死前告诉我的
Ryan told me on his deathbed.
明确告诉你  我那时就想杀了Slocum
And trust me, I wanted to kill Slocum
和组织的所有人
and every single member of the group
只为最后抓到你
just to get to you.
我当时想把你撕碎
I was gonna rip your guts out
然后用来刷墙
and wipe the walls with them.
但我的朋友 我的家人
But my friends, my family--
都提醒我  我最好别那么做
they reminded me that I'm better than that
正确的
and that the right thing to do
应该是慢慢将你诱入圈套  而不是马上杀了你
would be to lure you in, not kill you.
无论如何  都不能让nikita名单
Under no circumstances can she be allowed
从那所屋子里带出来
to get that list out of that house.
我不管你该做什么
I don't care what you have to do.
为了做到这些
And in order to do that,
我得让你感觉到我失去了我的方向
I needed you to feel that I'd lost my way.
我成为了多年前
I needed to become the destroyer
你所遇到的那个我
that you met all those years ago.
还记得她吗？
Remember her?
记得
I do.
她跟我已融为一体
She is a part of me.
一直会这样
And she always will be,
但她不是万能的
but she's not everything.
你让选择  我愿意成为哪一个
You asked me to choose, who will I be?
这就是我的选择
This is my choice.
还有对我忠心的人在外面
There are people out there loyal to me.
他们会找到我
They will find me.
却没人能找到你
No one will ever find you.
欢迎回到地下室
Welcome back to the basement...
Helen
Helen.
Nikita！
Nikita!
这是个很冒险的举动  让Marines带你下去吧
That was a risky move, letting the Marines take you down.
一直到现在  我感觉
Right up till then, I thought
你完全脱轨了
you had really gone off the rails.
很抱歉我们没能很快的让你进入这个圈子
I'm sorry we couldn't bring you into the loop sooner.
唯一的能够成功的办法就是
The only way this was going to work
每个人都买进去
was if everyone bought into it.
不用道歉
Don't apologize.
与我平常接触的那些人相比
Unlike the people I usually work with,
你们这些家伙可是实打实做事的
you guys actually get things done.
协调清除组织已经在38分钟前开始行动了
The coordinated sting started 38 minutes ago.
CIA  FBI  国际刑警组织都在协同作战
CIA, FBI, Interpol all working in concert
悄悄的带走世界范围内的所有复制品
to bring in the doubles around the world, quietly.
谢谢你  议员
Thank you, Senator.
不
No.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你的所有赦免都已经被签署了
Your pardons have all been signed.
这一篇历史已经结束了
This chapter of history is over,
新的开始都在等着你们
and a new one's begun, for all of you.
但是我们中的一个
All but one of us.
Ryan Fletcher的奉献已被认可
Ryan Fletcher's service has been recognized.
人们会铭记他的
He'll be remembered.
你见证了谎言
You saw the lies.
你知道总会有一个人
You knew there'd always be someone
会滥用势力
who would abuse their power.
这就是为什么你注意我们
That's why you looked to us.
他让我们成为更棒的英雄
He made us better heroes.
现在Ryan给了我们一份礼物…
Now Ryan has given us a gift--
自由
freedom.
演讲结束后有一辆车
There will be a car outside the west entrance
停在西入口外面
after the speech.
两个人在那儿驻守
Stationed two men there.
我看就没有这个必要了吧？是有关人权的会议
Is that really necessary? It's a human rights conference.
没人会寻衅滋事
They don't get that rowdy.
嘿  我只是尽我职责
Hey, I'm trying to be responsible.
这可不是一般人想做就做的工作
Isn't that what people with jobs do?
你需要钱
Hey, you need the money.
公司也不是那么的差劲
The company's not so bad either.
晚餐能晚点吗？
Dinner later?
为什么  你需要有人给你开酒吗？
Why, you need someone to open the wine?
我不喝酒  你应该了解我的
No, I don't drink, which you should know about me.
嗯
Hmm.
还有其他惊喜吗？
Any other surprises?
Alexandra Udinov
Alexandra Udinov.
现在我们终于在这个世界上
Now we can find our place
找到属于我们的地方  无论哪里
in the world, wherever that might be.
所以暗影行者就要走出阴影了
So Shadowwalker is coming out of the shadows.
算是放下它的一种方式吧  对吧
That's one way of putting it, yeah.
是不是意味着你合法了？
Does this mean you're going legit?
合法？
Legit?
我不知道
Yeah, I don't know.
我从来不循规蹈矩
I've never really done lockstep.
有个妞在伦敦等我
I've got a girl waiting for me in London.
她让我深信不疑的是
She convinced me sharing the code
分享代码是对的
was the right thing to do.
对 影网
Yes. Shadownet.
你这样决定会保护平民百姓
You claim this will protect regular folks
免受政府机关的监视吗？
against government agencies that spy on them?
这是指什么？
So this is what--
面向大众的数字自由？
digital freedom for the masses?
我说过它更像是…
I'd say more like...
开源的无政府状态
open-source anarchy.
我喜欢那样 写下来
Yeah, I like that. Write that down.
“开源的无政府状” 好
"Open-source anarchy." Okay.
“开”和“源”之间加道杠杠
Hyphen in between "Open" And "Source."
这会吓坏某些人
You know, this is gonna freak some people out.
好
Good.
很好
That's good.
尽管  自由是个可怕的事情
Freedom's a scary thing, though.
没人能回答  除了我们自己
We've got no one to answer to but ourselves.
我们已经回答他们了
We used to answer to them.
没人想要过继别人的孩  但是这个世界会要
The stepchild nobody wanted but the world needed.
这就是战争！没有士兵  我们就不能取得胜利
拿着
你觉得我们私奔他们会疯掉吗
You think they'll be mad we eloped?
好吧  我们好像没计划私奔啊
Well, it's not like we planned it.
我有个蜜月的好主意
I have an idea for the honeymoon.
现在我们终于自由了
Now that we're finally free,
知道为什么我们战斗的如此艰辛
I get why we fought so hard.
真正的礼物不是自由
The real gift isn't freedom.
而是对于自由我们该做些什么
It's what we get to do with it.
我还不了解你
I don't know about you,
但是无论如何  我都决不只是享受沙滩
but I could never just sit on a beach anyway.